<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Callum Taylor</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Callum Taylor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading data from HDX easily in a tidy format - hdxr and hdx_resource_csv</title>
      <link>/2017/06/11/downloading-datasets-from-hdx-in-an-easier-pipeline-and-a-tidy-format-hdxr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/11/downloading-datasets-from-hdx-in-an-easier-pipeline-and-a-tidy-format-hdxr/</guid>
      <description>An easier pipeline for Humanitarian Data Exchange, with a tidy formatI’ve been trying to make it easier to extract data from HDX in R, using tidyverse and ropensci packages. I’ve started compiling a mini-package called hdxr that wraps these pipelines up neatly.
I’ve added a new function today hdx_resource_csv that means to download datasets from HDX all you need to do is the following:
library(hdxr)hdx_connect()datasets &amp;lt;- hdx_package_search(term = &amp;quot;data title&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%hdx_resource_list() %&amp;gt;%hdx_resource_csv()I’ve described most of these functions in previous posts, but basically:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using sf, gganimate, and the Humanitarian Data Exchange to map ACLED data for Africa</title>
      <link>/2017/06/05/using-sf-gganimate-and-the-humanitarian-data-exchange-to-map-acled-data-for-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/05/using-sf-gganimate-and-the-humanitarian-data-exchange-to-map-acled-data-for-africa/</guid>
      <description>Mapping fatalities from violence in Africa in 2017In my previous post I showed how I was trying to get data directly from the Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX), in an R pipeline.
Here’s a quick example of what it allows you to do. The visualisations in this aren’t pretty, it’s mainly meant as an example of what you can easily do. I’m really enjoying using sf to plot maps in ggplot2, thanks to Matt Strimas-Mackey showing how to get that working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting data from Humanitarian Data Exchange in a reproducible R pipeline</title>
      <link>/2017/06/04/getting-data-from-humanitarian-data-exchange-in-a-reproducible-r-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/04/getting-data-from-humanitarian-data-exchange-in-a-reproducible-r-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Update: I’ve updated a couple of these functions, as they were messy and unreliable (they probably still are!). I’ve also put them together as a mini-package that you can install from github: hdxr. The code below is the OLD version, the up to date versions are on github. If you’ve ideas on how I should do it better, please let me know on github/twitter.
I’ve been trying to make it easier for me to get information from the Humanitarian Data Exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Package: hdxr</title>
      <link>/2017/06/04/mini-package-hdxr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/04/mini-package-hdxr/</guid>
      <description>Mini package - Mini postI realised that when I wrote this post, I should do something more sensible to share the code then put the text up in a blog. Writing a package seemed overkill though, and something you only do for ‘real code’.
But curiousity got the better of me, and after reading the go-to post for package writing, I thought I might as well try.
So here we are: hdxr</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting deprivation in Scotland, using geofacet and sf in R</title>
      <link>/2017/05/29/plotting-deprivation-in-scotland-using-geofacet-and-sf-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/29/plotting-deprivation-in-scotland-using-geofacet-and-sf-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Using the geofacet package to plot deprivation in Scotland by Health BoardsA few months ago, when I was first starting to learn to use R, I tried looking at the data from the Scottish Index of Multiple Deprivation. The Scottish Government split Scotland up into 6976 equally populated “data zones” (not quite neighbourhoods, but pretty close), and ranked them from most deprived (1), to least deprived (6976)
Recently I’ve gone back to the same files, to see if what I’ve learnt has made it easier to look at deprivation in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This shows what I&amp;rsquo;m procrastinating with and pretending counts as work.
This is a personal site built using the blogdown package. The theme is from @spf13/hyde</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archive/</guid>
      <description> Blog Posts </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>